Ehrmann, Henry W. (Heinrich); Papers ger013
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann, 1931-1989; 4; 85 file folders
  - Publications, 4.2
    - "France Faces New Stalemate", 1951 June 24 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 50)
    - "Nobel Prize Winner [Leon Jouhaux]. Man of Many Facets", 1951 December 2 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 51)
    - "The French Peasant and Communism", 1952 March (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 52)
    - Hannah Arendt.The Origins of Totalitarianism; Eugen Kogon. Der SS-Staat. Das System der deutschen Konzentrationslager (reviews), 1952 April (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 53)
    - "The French Peasant and Communism", 1952 July 12 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 54)
    - "The Convention at Dortmund", 1952 October 8 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 55)
    - "Ollenhauer ... Europe's 'No' Man", 1952 November 23 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 56)
    - "Report on the French Economy", 1953 July 17 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 57)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1954-1974 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 58)
    - "The French Trade Associations and the Ratification of the Schumann Plan", 1954 July (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 59)
    - "Way to Strengthen U.N. Presented by Commission", 1958 January 9 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 60)
    - "Pressure Groups in France", 1958 September (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 61)
    - "Pressures in a Divided France", 1958 October (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 62)
    - "Les partis américains et la politique étrangère", 1959 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 63)
    - "Une analyse americaine du patrionat français", 1959 March (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 64)
    - "The reign of DeGaulle II", Spring 1959 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 65)
    - "Administration et Groupes de Pression", 1960 January-1960 February (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 66)
    - "French Bureaucracy and Organized Interests", 1961 March (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 67)
    - "On democracy in France", Spring 1961 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 68)
    - "Ehrmann Looks at Future of France after DeGaulle", 1961 May 26 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 69)
    - "Whither France. DeGaulle Can't Stay in Power Forever", 1961 October 20 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 70)
    - "Die Verfassungsentwicklung im Frankreich der Fünften Republik", 1962 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 71)
    - "Funktionswandel der demokratischen Institutionen in den USA", ca. 1962 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 72)
    - "Civil Law Systems", ca. 1962-1963 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 73)
    - "Bureaucracy and interest groups in the decision-making process of the Fifth Republic", 1963 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 74)
    - "Direct Democracy in France", 1963 December (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 75)
    - "II. European Views of the Atlantic Alliance", 1965 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 76)
    - "Interest Groups", 1968 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 77)
    - "Latest Course Guide Offers Useful Advice", 1970 November 2 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 78)
    - Undated (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 79)
      "Watergate. Les instances consitutionnelles" (1974); "États-Unis. Les pouvoirs présidentiels après le Watergate" (1975).
    - "French Communism: Theory and Practice", 1978 May-1978 June (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 80)
    - "Die Entwicklung der Verfassungsgerichtsbarkeit im Frankreich der Fünften Republik", 1981 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 81)
    - Karlheinz Reif.Parteiregierung in Frankreich (review), 1983 October (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 82)
    - "Chapter 4: Judician Activism in a Divided Society: the Rule of Law in the Weimar Republic", ca. 1983-1984 (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 83)
    - "Die Grenzen der Justiz im Wohlfahrtsstaat -- eine amerikanische Debatte", 1984 May (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 84)
    - "Unterschiedliche Regierungsformen in systemtheoretischer Analyse", Undated (Box 5 (4-Miscellaneous Works Written by Ehrmann), Folder 85)
- Lectures, 1947-1988; 5; 19 file folders
  This series reflects Ehrmann's lifelong teaching career at American universities and overseas. A large portion of the material originates from Political Science courses taught by Ehrmann at the University of Colorado in Boulder, Dartmouth College in Hanover, NH, and - as a visiting professor - at the universities in Paris, Berlin, and at the University of California in Berkeley. There is also a significant collection of single lectures given in various countries over the period of four decades. Some of the lectures are written in French and German. The series also includes a folder with syllabi and examination handouts.
  - Single Lectures, 1947-1986; 5.1; 7 file folders
    The sub-series contains single lectures dealing with the political, social, and legal systems of France, Germany, and the United States. There is also a large number of lectures on international affairs.
    - International Affairs -- Single Lectures, 1947-1960; Undated; 1961-1983 (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 1-2)
    - Single Lectures on the USA, 1948-1968; Undated (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 3)
    - Single Lectures on France, 1949-1962; Undated; 1963-1986 (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 4-5)
    - Single Lectures on Germany, 1949-1984 (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 6)
    - Single Lectures -- Miscellaneous, 1949-1960; Undated (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 7)
  - University Courses and Syllabi, 1953-1988; 5.2; 12 file folders
    The material (frequently undated) pertains to the following university courses: International Law, International Organization, International Law and Organization, Comparative Politics: Europe, Introduction to Political Science, Comparative Politics, Verfassungslehre und Verfassungspraxis in den USA und der französischen fünften Republik (Constitutional Theory and Practice in the USA and the French Fifth Republic), Le Système Politique Français, and Politics in France. The lectures are accompanied by numerous handwritten and typed additions as well as newspaper clippings.
    - International Law, Undated (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 8)
    - International Organization, Undated (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 9)
    - International Law and Organization, 1955; Undated (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Materials and Additions to the Course of International Law and Organization, 1953-1965; Undated (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 11)
    - Verfassungslehre und Verfassungspraxis in den USA und der französischen fünften Republik (Berlin, 1967 (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 12)
    - Comparative Politics: Europe, 1969-1980; Undated (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 13)
    - Comparative Politics: Europe -- Notes on Course Books and Additions to the Lectures, Undated (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Articles and Other Materials Pertaining to the Course of Comparative Politics, 1976-1980; Undated (Box 6 (5-Lectures), Folder 15)
    - Le Système Politique Français (Paris, 1973-1974 (Box 7 (5-Lectures), Folder 1)
    - Introduction to Political Science, Comparative Politics, 1974-1977; bound volume (Box 7 (5-Lectures), Folder 2)
    - Politics in France (UC Berkeley, 1978 (Box 7 (5-Lectures), Folder 3)
    - Syllabi and Examinations, 1960-1988; Undated (Box 7 (5-Lectures), Folder 4)